# ABOUT ME My work background has

My work background has been people facing roles that focus heavily on communication; whereas in my free time I prefer to do less talking, spending it reading, playing video games, and seeing musical theatre shows. I explored different roles since leaving college and took my favourite things from each of them when I left:

- creativity
- structure
- fast-paced work
- space for learning new things

I found all of this in software engineering. I chose coding because it is an outlet for creativity that I have not found in previous roles, as well as being intellectually challenging. I love the problem-solving aspect as it keeps me motivated and energetic.







# RAPHAELLA D'ALESSANDRO

# **EDUCATION**

### Makers Academy (April 2022 - August 2022)

- Full stack Software Engineering
- Tailored training in feedback, communication, and teamwork
- Pair programming and group work using agile methodologies
- Test-driven development: unit & integration testing
- Object-oriented languages: Ruby & JavaScript
- Solid debugging processes
- Databases: document database & relational database management system
- Git workflow

# SheCodes (May 2021 - August 2021)

- Series of front-end web development courses: Basics, Plus, Responsive, and React.
- Focusing on responsive web design, flexbox, SEO, API, hosting, GitHub, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React

### Richmond Upon Thames College (2016 - 2018)

• Level 3 Health & Social Care BTEC - Distinction\*, Distinction

### University of West London (2016)

Musical Theatre Grade 8 – Distinction

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Administrator - Talent & People • Havas Life Medicom (January 2020 - June 2021)

- Attention to detail allowed me to create detailed reports for absence, compliance, and objectives & write contracts
- Time management skills helped when balancing the recruitment and onboarding of several new starters at once.
- Communication skills assisted me in put candidates at ease during screening calls.
- I used presentation skills when running induction sessions for new starters.
- I took on the additional responsibility of becoming a Diversity & Inclusion Ambassador. This included writing pieces for internal website focusing on LGBTQ+ issues.

### Receptionist • Kingston Lodge Hotel & Bingham Riverhouse (May 2019 - October 2019)

- My interpersonal communication skills when greeting and interacting with guests made their experience friendly and seamless.
- Leadership and active listening were useful when training new team members.
- Meticulous eye for detail helped me balance and reconciling PDQ transactions against the system for the reception, bar, and restaurant.

### Administration & Social Media Marketing • Various West End Producers (October 2018 – April 2019)

- Analytical skills and creativity allowed me to grow follower counts and engagement on multiple platforms incl. Twitter & Instagram.
- Time management was key when updating websites, managing inboxes, and responding to enquiries.
- Project management skills assisted me with the planning & marketing of events.

# Founder & Director • Dreamrole productions (May 2016 - September 2018)

- Attention to detail when handling budgets.
- Project management and time management coordinating events.
- Communication skills when casting, planning, and liaising with venues & providers.

I worked in hospitality roles whilst still in full-time education which helped me develop my communication, problem solving and most importantly time management skills further